Guide to the Women's National Book Association Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Women's National Book Association Records
1917-2011.
Women's National Book Association.
50 linear ft. (117 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, 6th Fl. East, 535 West 114th St., New York, NY. 10027
MS#1372
4079627
The Women’s National Book Association Papers document the history and work of the Women’s National Book Association from their founding in 1917 until today. The organization is active in promoting women in the book industry through awards and programs to increase women’s participation in the profession and the role of women in publishing and other book-related fields.
Historical Note
The Women’s National Book Association (WNBA) was formed in 1917 as a group to promote reading and the role of women in the book industry. They currently have nine chapters across the country as well as a number of corresponding and supporting members. The WNBA has had a number of important members including Pearl S. Buck and Alice B. Toklas, and most of the members are active authors or editors.
The chapters of WNBA are based in Boston, Charlotte, Dallas, Detroit, Los Angeles, Nashville, New York, San Francisco, Seattle and Washington D.C. New York City was the first chapter, and remains the center of the national organization. Many of the chapters were founded by former members who moved to new places and organized local women involved in the book industry into the group. The organization continues to grow, the Seattle Chapter was founded in 2008 and Charlotte in 2009.
The WNBA gives several awards every year. The WNBA Award formerly the Constance Lindsay Skinner Award) is given to a woman who works in the book industry full time, and has done exceptional work in promoting books beyond the responsibilities of her job. The WNBA Eastman Grant gives money to library associations to support the training and professional development of librarians in states where there is a WNBA chapter. The WNBA Pannell Award is given to booksellers who work to promote interest in books among children and young adults.
The WNBA is also a Non-Governmental Organization member of the United Nations, and is active in working with the United Nations to promote literacy across the world. They are particularly involved in work with UNICEF and were active in the International Book Year and the International Year of the Child.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence, memoranda, photographs, meeting minutes, membership materials, publications, financial information, reports and other materials important to the day-to-day operation of the organization. The bulk of the materials document the major awards given by the WNBA, the Lucile M. Pannell Award, the Constance Lindsay Skinner Award (now the WNBA Award), and the Amy Loveman Award. Each chapter has numerous materials from their founding until today, and the collection includes the important information about membership, how the chapter was run, events and important guests and speakers. Some important correspondents from the early documents include Catherine Drinker Bowen, Howard Fast, Marchette Chute, Mary Ellen Chase, Marguerite Henry, Abraham Ribicoff, Irita Van Doren, Beatrice Warde, Pearl S. Buck, Edward Weeks, and Alice B. Toklas.
Arrangement
Materials arranged into 6 series:
Series I: Materials Received from 1917-1983
Series II: Materials Received from 1978-1982
Series III: Materials Received 1982-1984
Series IV: Materials Received in 1984
Series V: Materials Received in 1986
Series VI: Subject Files, National Chapter, 1963-1991
Series VII: Materials Received 1992-2011
The collection is arranged into 6 series based on the material’s accession date and with a separate series for subject files received from the national chapter. Most of the materials are arranged within the series by chapter or by event, with some separation of types of materials including correspondence and published materials. Some chapters separated their materials more specifically into groupings of by-laws, minutes, events and membership, while other chapters are only grouped by chapter and date. Some of the early materials are cataloged individually and the Pearl S. Buck letter is on microfilm.
Subjects
Bowen, Catherine Drinker, 1897-1973.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Chute, Marchette Gaylord, 1909-; Chase, Mary Ellen, 1887-1973.; Fast, Howard, 1914-2003.; Henry, Marguerite, 1902-1997.; Ribicoff, Abraham, 1910-1998.; Toklas, Alice B.; Van Doren, Irita.; Warde, Beatrice, 1900-1969.; Weeks, Edward, 1898-1989.; Book industries and trade.; Booksellers and bookselling.; Literature.; Publishers and publishing.; Women in literature.; Audio cassettes.; Brochures.; Bylaws.; Financial records.; Minutes.; Newsletters.; Photographs.; Programs.; Questionnaires.; Reports.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches.; Tables.; Authors.; Publishers.; Women authors.
Access Restrictions
Collection has no restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Records WNBA Gift
Alternate Formats
Pearl S. Buck letter is on microfilm.
Gift of officers and members of the Association, 1974-1990.
- Series I: Materials Received from 1917-1983
  - ABA Hospitality Booth, undated (Box 1)
  - ALA Tea, undated (Box 1)
  - Anti-Defamation League/WNBA, undated (Box 1)
  - Attendance, undated (Box 1)
  - Board Meetings, 1954-1955 (Box 1a)
  - Book sales, undated (Box 1a)
  - Book shelves, undated (Box 1a)
  - Bookselling course, undated (Box 1a)
  - Bookwoman-related materials (3 Folders), undated (Box 1a)
  - Committee on Reading Development, undated (Box 1a)
  - Constitution, undated (Box 1a)
  - Corresponding secretary-meeting notices, undated (Box 2)
  - Courses, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary, undated (Box 2)
  - Freedom to Read, undated (Box 2)
  - History, undated (Box 2)
  - Hospitalized Veterans, undated (Box 2)
  - Indiana University Workshop, undated (Box 3)
  - Information Kit for Local Sponsors, undated (Box 3)
  - International Plans, undated (Box 3)
  - Job Consultant, undated (Box 3)
  - Helen Lee, undated (Box 3)
  - Amy Loveman Award
    - Award, undated (Box 3)
    - Award, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
    - Award, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Award, Entries, undated (Box 4)
    - Award, Copy for Forms, undated (Box 4)
    - Award, Paid bills, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Mailing List, undated (Box 4)
  - Meetings, undated (Box 4)
  - Membership, 1951-1952 (Box 4a)
  - Membership Drive, undated (Box 4a)
  - Membership Lists, undated (Box 4a)
  - Members, Sustaining, undated (Box 4a)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4a)
  - Nashville visit, undated (Box 5)
  - National Board, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - National Board, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - National Membership Drive, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Nominating Committee, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Nominations for National Officers, undated (Box 5)
  - Old material, undated (Box 5)
  - Outing, 1950 (Box 5)
  - President's Duties, undated (Box 5)
  - President's Newsletter, 1959 (Box 5)
  - President's Newsletter, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - President's Newsletter, extras, undated (Box 5)
  - Program, undated (Box 5)
  - Program, 1950-1951 (Box 5)
  - Skinner, Constance L., Dinner, 1951-1973 (Box 6)
  - Skinner, Constance L., Dinner, 1951-1973 (Box 6a)
  - Special Projects, 1959-1960 (Box 6b-c)
  - Status of Women, undated (Box 6b-c)
  - Treasurer's Reports, undated (Box 7)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1955-1959 (Box 7)
  - United Nations (2 Folders), undated (Box 7)
  - Young Bookwoman, undated (Box 7)
  - Binghamton Chapter, undated (Box 7a)
  - Boston Chapter, undated (Box 7a)
  - Cleveland Chapter, undated (Box 8)
  - Detroit Chapter, undated (Box 8)
  - Grand Rapids Chapter, undated (Box 8)
  - Little Rock Chapter, undated (Box 8)
  - Nashville Chapter,undated (Box 8)
  - New Chapters, undated (Box 8)
  - New Chapter procedures, undated (Box 8)
  - New York Chapter, undated (Box 8)
  - Proposed new chapters, undated (Box 8)
  - San Francisco Chapter, undated (Box 8)
  - Chronological File, 1920-1962 (Box 9)
  - Chronological File, 1962-1964 (Box 9a)
  - Chronological File, 1965-1969 (Box 10)
  - Chronological File, 1970-1972 (Box 11)
  - General Financial Records, 1961-1973 (Box 11)
  - Chronological File, 1970-1975 (Box 12)
  - Chronological File, 1971-1973 (Box 13)
  - Chronological File, 1973-1975, 1975-1977 (minutes) (Box 14)
  - Printed miscellany, undated (Box 14)
  - Scrapbooks, 1917-1933 (Box 93)
  - Scrapbooks, 1934-1943 (Box 94)
  - Scrapbooks, 1944-1946, 1953-1956 (Box 95)
  - Scrapbooks, 1951-1954 (Box 96)
  - Scrapbooks, 1956-1964 (Box 97)
  - Scrapbooks, 1958-1961 (Box 98)
  - Scrapbooks, 1964-1968, 1983 (Box 99)
- Series II: Materials Received 1978-1981
  - American Library Association, 1976-1979 (Box 15)
  - Association of American Publishers, two volumes, undated (Box 15)
  - Board of Managers, undated (Box 16)
  - Bookwoman--Correspondence and related materials, undated, (3 Folders) (Box 16)
  - Brochures, undated (Box 17)
  - Catalyst, undated (Box 17)
  - Children's Books Northeast, undated (Box 17)
  - Clippings and Reference Materials, undated (Box 17)
  - Constance Lindsay Skinner%tb %te An… H. Eastman, undated (Box 17)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, undated (Box 17)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, undated (Box 18)
  - Corresponding members, 1976-1978 (Box 18)
  - Eastman, Ann H.--Correspondence and Miscellaneous files, 1974-1979 (Box 18)
  - Eastman, Ann H.--Speeches, undated (Box 19)
  - Ethnicity, undated (Box 19)
  - Financial Papers, undated (Box 20)
  - Geiser, Elizabeth (National vice-president), undated (Box 20)
  - Gross, Mason, undated (Box 20)
  - History, undated (Box 20)
  - Hospitalized Veteran's Project, undated (Box 20)
  - Labor, U.S. Department of, undated (Box 20)
  - Loveman, Amy-- Award, undated (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20)
  - National Advisory Council on Women's Education Programs, undated (Box 20)
  - National Book Award, undated (Box 20)
  - National Council of Teachers of English--Conferences, undated (Box 21)
  - National Membership, 1974-1976 (Box 22)
  - Newsletter, undated (Box 22)
  - Oakley, Adeline (National secretary), undated (Box 22)
  - Officers, undated (Box 22)
  - President's Newsletter and Reports, undated (Box 22)
  - Procedure Manual, undated (Box 22)
  - Programs and Goals, undated (Box 22)
  - Publicity, undated (Box 22)
  - Publishing and Library Data, undated (Box 22)
  - Reading is Fundamental, undated (Box 22)
  - Skinner, Constance L.--Award, undated (Box 22A)
  - Status of Women, undated (Box 22B)
  - Status of Women, undated (Box 23)
  - Treasurer, National--Files, 1978 (Box 23)
  - United Nations--General, undated (Box 23A)
  - United Nations, 1975-1976 (Box 23A)
  - United Nations--International Women's Year, undated (Box 23A)
  - United Nations-International Year of the Child, undated (Box 24)
  - U.N./U.S.A., undated (Box 24)
  - Where Now Before & After (newsletter), undated (Box 24)
  - Women at Work, undated (Box 24)
  - Data Sheets, chapters, undated (Box 24A)
  - Boston Chapter, undated (Box 24A)
  - Cleveland Chapter, undated (Box 24A)
  - Detroit Chapter, undated (Box 24A)
  - Grand Rapids Chapter, undated (Box 25)
  - Grand Rapids Chapter, undated (Box 25A)
  - Little Rock Chapter, undated (Box 25B)
  - Nashville Chapter, undated (Box 25B)
  - New York Chapter, undated (Box 25B)
  - New York Chapter, undated (Box 26)
  - Pittsburgh Chapter, undated (Box 27)
  - San Francisco Chapter, undated (Box 28)
  - Southern California Chapter, undated (Box 28)
  - Washington/Baltimore Chapter, Undated (Box 28)
  - Chronological File, 1970-1973 (Box 29)
  - Chronological File, 1974 (Box 30)
  - Photographs and documents, undated (Box 30)
  - Helen Watts Birthday invitation, 1973 (Box 30)
- Series III: Materials Received 1982-1984
  - The American Book Awards, 1980 (Box 31)
  - American Library Association-Dallas, TX 1979 (Box 31)
  - Archives, 1974-1976 (Box 31)
  - Board, National, 1974-1979 (Box 31)
  - Board Meeting--Roanoke, Va, 1979 (Box 32)
  - Bookwoman, editorial correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 32)
  - Brochure, 1977 (Box 32)
  - A Brief History Women's National Book Association, by Anne J. Richter, 1975 (Box 32)
  - Budget, 1975-1979 (Box 32)
  - Chapter employer identification numbers, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Corresponding membership, 1979 (Box 33)
  - Committee on Programs and Goals, 1975-1978 (Box 33)
  - Director of Public Affairs, 1980-1982 (Box 33)
  - General inquiries, 1979-1980 (Box 33)
  - Materials, 1974-1980 (Box 33)
  - Meeting minutes, 1968-1980 (Box 33)
  - Membership List, 1975-1982 (Box 33)
  - Modern Language Association--New York City, 1978 (Box 34)
  - Modern Language Association--San Francisco, 1979 (Box 34)
  - Procedures manual, 1979-1980 (Box 34)
  - President (Ann Heidbreder Eastman), 1976-1979 (Box 34)
  - President (Ann Heidbreder Eastman), 1979-1980 (Box 35)
  - President--Past (Mary V. Gaver), undated (Box 35)
  - Presidential Newsletter, 1976-1980 (Box 35)
  - Secretary & Public relations, 1978-1980 (Box 35)
  - Constance Lindsay Skinner
    - Award, 1973-1976 (Box 35)
    - Award, 1978-1979 (Box 36)
    - Book--Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 36)
    - Book--Data for bibliographies and drafts of essays, undated (Box 36)
    - Book--Ann H. Eastman file, 1979-1980 (Box 36)
    - Letter to H.H. Watts--printed for 1980 award, undated (Box 36)
  - Treasurer, 1978-1980 (Box 37)
  - United Nations--International Year of the Child, 1979 (Box 37)
  - Vice President, 1975-1976 (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 37)
  - Binghamton Chapter, 1974-1982 (Box 38)
  - Boston Chapter, 1977-1980 (Box 38)
  - Chicago Chapter, 1976-1979 (Box 38)
  - Cleveland Chapter, 1979-1984 (Box 38)
  - Detroit Chapter, 1979-1982 (Box 38)
  - Grand Rapids Chapter,1978-1979 (Box 38)
  - Memphis Chapter, 1977 (Box 38)
  - Nashville Chapter-- cookbook, 1979-1984 (Box 38)
  - New York City Chapter, 1976-1979 (Box 38)
  - New York City Chapter, 1979-1984 (Box 39)
  - Pittsburgh Chapter, 1979-1980 (Box 39)
  - San Francisco Chapter, 1978-1984 (Box 39)
  - Washington/Baltimore Chapter, 1978-1984 (Box 39)
  - Los Angeles Chapter, 1975-1981 (Box 40)
  - Los Angeles Chapter, 1982-1985 (Box 40A)
  - San Francisco Chapter, 1984 (Box 40A)
- Series IV: Materials received in 1984
  - Board--National--Minutes and Photographs, 1973-1981 (Box 41)
  - By-Laws, undated (Box 41)
  - Chapter Data Sheets, 1978-1979 (Box 41)
  - Correspondence Secretary, 1977-1980 (Box 41)
  - Financial Papers--Budget, 1981-1982, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
  - Financial Papers--Expense Reports, 1981-1983 (Box 41)
  - Incorporation and Tax Exemption File, 1975-1980 (Box 42)
  - Incorporation and Tax Exemption File--Legal Fees, undated (Box 42)
  - Membership Lists, 1975-1979 (Box 43)
  - Membership lists, 1980-1982 (Box 44)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Awards, undated (Box 45)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Estate, undated (Box 45)
  - Presidential Newsletter, 1980 (Box 45)
  - Procedures Manual, 1974-1980 (Box 45)
  - Constance Lindsay Skinner book--Sales and Promotion, undated (Box 45)
  - President's Correspondence, undated (Box 46)
  - Treasurer's Report, undated (Box 46)
  - Treasurer's Correspondence, undated (Box 46)
  - Vice President's Correspondence, undated (Box 46)
- Series V: Materials Received in 1986
  - Claire Friedland files (U.N. representative), 1973-1981 (Box 47)
    - Copenhagen (Box 47)
    - International Year of the Child, (2 Folders) (Box 47)
    - International Women's Year, 1975 (Box 47)
    - United Nations Association (Box 47)
    - United Nations--Non-Government Organizations (Box 47)
  - WNBA, 1984-1985 (Box 48)
  - American Booksellers Association Convention, 2 June 1983, (2 Folders) (Box 48)
  - American Booksellers Association, 7-10 June 1980 (Box 48)
  - Board Meeting, 1982 (Box 48)
  - Board Meeting, 1983 (Box 48)
  - Board Meeting, 1984 (Box 48)
  - Board Meeting, 1984-1985 (Box 48)
  - National Board Meeting, Los Angeles, 1981, (2 Folders) (Box 49)
  - National Board Meeting, Nashville, 1978 (Box 49)
  - National Board Meeting, New York City, 1980 (Box 49)
  - Bookwoman--Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 49)
  - Breakfast, San Francisco, 27 June 1981 (Box 50)
  - Brochure, 1982 (Box 50)
  - By-laws, September 1980 (Box 50)
  - Copies, WNBA Materials, 1980 (Box 50)
  - Corresponding Members, 1981 (Box 50)
  - Sylvia Cross Newsletter, undated (Box 50)
  - Ann H. Eastman, Past President, undated (Box 50)
  - Finances, 1980-1982 (Box 51)
  - Mary Glenn Hearne, 1981 (Box 51)
  - Amy Loveman, Award, 1980 (Box 51)
  - Modern Language Association
    - Conference of Editors of Learned Journals Program, 1985 (Box 51)
    - National Session, Houston, 1980 (Box 51)
    - Women in Scholarly Publishing, Los Angeles, 1982 (Box 51)
    - Women in Scholarly Publishing, New York, 1981 (Box 51)
    - Women in Scholarly Publishing, New York, 1983 (Box 51)
    - Women in Scholarly Publishing, Washington, 1984 (Box 51)
  - New York Chapter--Survey on the status of women, 1983 (Box 51)
  - National Newsletter, undated (Box 52)
  - Procedure Manual, 1981 (Box 52)
  - Sustaining Members, September 1980 (Box 52)
  - United Nations International Year of the Child, undated (Box 52)
  - Constance L. Skinner Award (Box 53)
    - Award, 1981-1982 (Box 53)
    - Award Evaluation, 1983 (Box 53)
    - Anne Pellowski, New York City, 1980, (2 Folders) (Box 53)
  - Book, undated (Box 53)
  - Book--Songs of the Coast Dwellers, undated (Box 53)
  - Book Brochures, undated (Box 54)
  - Book Brochures--Materials Used in Draft, undated (Box 54)
  - Book--Marketing and Promotion, May 1980 (Box 54)
  - Procedure Manual, March 1980 (Box 54)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Award (Box 55)
    - Award No. 2, 1984 (Box 55)
    - Award No. 3, 1985, (3 Folders) (Box 55)
    - Juror's Evaluation Forms, undated (Box 55)
    - Jury, 1985 (Box 55)
    - Address labels, 1984 (Box 56)
    - Advisory Committee, 9-10 June 1981 (Box 56)
    - Application, 1984 (Box 56)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 56)
    - Jury No. 2, 1984 (Box 56)
    - Procedures, undated (Box 56)
    - Publicity, 1984 (Box 56)
    - Archival and Historical, 1981 (Box 57)
    - Entrant Correspondence and Letter of Regret, 1983 (Box 57)
    - First Award, 1983, (2 Folders) (Box 57)
    - General Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 57)
    - Second (working) Committee, 1983 (Box 57)
    - Second Committee Correspondence, 1983 (Box 57)
    - Administration, 1982-1983 (Box 58)
    - Application Forms, undated (Box 58)
    - Publicity, 1983 (Box 58)
    - Jury No. 1, 1983 (Box 58)
    - Rafe Martin, First Winner, 1983 (Box 58)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 58)
  - School Application Request, 1982-1983 (Box 58)
  - Cross/Paul presidential files, 1978-1986 (Box 58)
  - Award, 1984 (Box 59)
  - Award, 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 59)
  - Award Ceremony, undated (Box 59)
  - Amy Loveman Award, undated (Box 59)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Award, Articles, undated (Box 59)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Award, 1983 (Box 59)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Award, 1984 (Box 60)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Award, 1985-1986 (Box 60)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Estate, undated (Box 60)
  - Lucile M. Pannell Estate (Trust), 1981-1983 (Box 60)
  - Constance L. Skinner Award, 1982 (Box 60)
  - Constance L.Skinner Award--Planning, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
  - Constance L. Skinner Book, undated (Box 60)
  - Board Meeting, 1982 (Box 60)
  - Board Meeting--Planning, 1983 (Box 60)
  - Board Meeting--Planning, 1984 (Box 60)
  - Board Meeting--Reports, 1985 (Box 61)
  - Board Meeting--Room Request, 1986 (Box 61)
  - Bookwoman
    - Advertising Information, undated (Box 61)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 61)
    - J. Crawford, 1982-1984 (Box 61)
    - By-laws Procedure, undated (Box 61)
    - By-laws Revision, 1982-1983 (Box 61)
    - Career Patterns in Publishing, undated (Box 61)
  - Center for National Security Studies, undated (Box 62)
  - Binghamton Chapter, undated (Box 62)
  - Boston Chapter, 1983 (Box 62)
  - Boston Chapter, 1984-1986 (Box 62)
  - By-laws, 1984 (Box 62)
  - Cleveland Chapter, undated (Box 62)
  - Detroit Chapter, undated (Box 62)
  - Data Sheets from Chapters, undated (Box 62)
  - Data Sheets from Chapters, 1982-1983 (Box 62)
  - Data Sheets from Chapters, 1983-1984 (Box 62)
  - Los Angeles Chapter, 1983-1984 (Box 62)
  - Los Angeles Chapter, 1984-1986 (Box 62)
  - Minneapolis Chapter, undated (Box 63)
  - Nashville Chapter, 1984-1985 (Box 63)
  - New York Chapter, 1983-1986 (Box 63)
  - Reports--Board and Treasurer, 1981-1982 (Box 63)
  - Reports--Presidents and Treasurers, undated (Box 63)
  - San Francisco Chapter, undated (Box 63)
  - Seattle/Tacoma Chapter, undated (Box 63)
  - Washington/Baltimore Chapter, 1984-1986 (Box 63)
  - Washington--Maricle, Kevin--Telephone Calls, 1983-1984 (Box 63)
  - Committee Correspondence, undated (Box 63)
  - Committee Nomination, 1980-1986 (Box 63)
  - Committee Nomination, 1984 (Box 63)
  - Committee Nominations, 1986 (Box 63)
  - Education for Publishing, undated (Box 64)
  - Goals and Objectives, undated (Box 64)
  - Publicity, undated (Box 64)
  - 70th Anniversary Committee, undated (Box 64)
  - WNBA Awards Committee, undated (Box 64)
  - Budget, undated (Box 64)
  - Finance--Budget, 1978-1982 (Box 64)
  - Finance--Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 64)
  - Financial, 1984-1985 (Box 64)
  - General Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 64)
  - General Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 64)
  - General Correspondence, 1984 (Box 64)
  - Listing in Publications, 1982-1984 (Box 65)
  - Memorial Fund, undated (Box 65)
  - Memos from Sylvia Cross, undated (Box 65)
  - National Brochure, 1982-1984 (Box 65)
  - National Letterhead, 1982-1983 (Box 65)
  - National Officers
    - Past President, M. Hearne, 1982-1983 (Box 65)
    - Sample Form Letters (Box 65)
    - Secretary (Box 65)
    - Treasurer, Sandy Souza, 1982-1983 (Box 65)
    - Vice President, Sandy Paul, 1982-1983 (Box 65)
  - Presidential
    - Expense Reports, 6/1983-5/1984 (Box 65)
    - General Correspondence, June 1982-May 31, 1983 (Box 65)
  - General Correspondence, June 1983-December 1984 (Box 66)
  - General Correspondence, December 1983-May 1984 (Box 66)
  - Memos from President, 6 July 1982-May 1983 (Box 66)
  - Newsletters
    - July 1982-May 1983 (Box 66)
    - August 1982-10 June 1983 (Box 66)
    - July 1983-May 1984 (Box 66)
    - July 1984-May 1985 (Box 66)
    - 1984-1986 (Box 66)
  - Printed Material (Box 66)
  - ABA-WNBA Panel, 1983 (Box 67)
  - ALA-Breakfast, 1982-1983 (Box 67)
  - ALA-Breakfast, 1983 (remaining materials) (Box 67)
  - ALA-Breakfast, 1984 (Box 67)
  - ALA-Breakfast, 1985 (Box 67)
  - MLA-WNBA Panel, 1983-1984 (Box 67)
  - MLA-WNBA Panel, 1984 (Box 67)
  - MLA-WNBA Panel, 1985 (Box 67)
  - MLA-WNBA Panel, 1986 (Box 67)
  - Savvy magazine (Box 67)
  - Sustaining Members
    - Renewal Request and Invoice (Box 67)
    - Send Money to Treasurer (Box 67)
    - Contributions Requested, 1982-1983 (Box 67)
    - Corresponding Members, 1986 (Box 67)
    - Declined to Renew (Box 67)
    - Drive (Box 67)
    - Mailing Labels (Box 67)
    - New Solicitation (Box 67)
    - Paid, A-H, 1982-1983 (Box 68)
    - Paid, I-Z, 1982-1983 (Box 68)
    - Paid, A-H, 1983-1984 (Box 68)
    - Paid, I-Z, 1983-1984 (Box 68)
    - Paid, 1984-1985 (Box 68)
    - Renewals Request, January 1983-1984 (Box 68)
    - Renewals Request, March 1983-1984 (Box 68)
    - Renewals Request, November 1985 (Box 68)
    - Schedules (Box 68)
  - United Nations/non-government organizations, 1982-1984 (Box 68)
  - Women's Leadership Institute, undated (Box 68)
  - Book Woman Files, 1984-1986 (Box 69)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 69)
  - Annual Reports to Board, 1985-1986 (Box 69)
  - Foul. Ms., Etc., 1984 (Box 69)
  - Foul. Ms., Etc., 1985 (Box 69)